## **WORK HISTORY**

# **Product Manager - Contract**

BuildingBloques | March 2022 till Present

- Secured and closed an international contract for BuildingBloques to develop a mobile and web application for one of their clients in the US.
- Assumed the role of a Product Manager who is overseeing the design of the Mobile and Web Application.
- Conducted interviews to get the best talents within the specifications and budget of the client.
- Currently overseeing a team of Mobile, Web and Backend developers who are building the mobile and web application of the company.

## Frontend Developer - Contract

JournalsYourWay | February 2022 till Present

- Designed and developed an e-commerce website for an event/wedding planner and author as a store front for her custom Journals and Notebooks.
- Implementation of payment gateways.
- · Search engine optimization of the site.
- Continued maintenance of the website.

# Frontend Developer - Contract

KWLC | December 2021 to March 2022

- Worked as a Frontend Developer, converting all the website design on figma to React/Typescript components.
- Contributed to the redesigning of the website in the absence of the web designer.
- Contributed to and reviewed codes while accessing the impact of submitted changes.

## Frontend Developer - Freelance

AFRIMAX | August 2021 to December 2021

- Worked as a contract developer in a small tech firm focused on non-profit organizations and small businesses.
- Specialized in moving mission-critical business operations to the cloud.
- Worked hand in hand with the project manager to ensure quality provision of web applications.

#### Frontend Developer - Intern

I4G x Zuri x HNG Internship | March to October 2021

- Collaborated with UI/UX designers, Frontend Developers and other members of the project team to develop the site concept interface design and architecture of the website.
- Designed and developed a web application that provides school information for students in Nigeria.
- Web Application building in coordination with the engineering team to deliver a quality product for Zuri.chat.
- Planned and created features for the youtube music and video plugin, and workspace admin settings that are currently in use on the web app.

# **LILIAN OKEKE**

## FRONTEND DEVELOPER

## **PROFILE SUMMARY**

I am a front-end web developer with robust problem-solving skills and proven experience in creating and designing web applications.

I am mostly interested in bridging the gap between organizations, businesses and their users by creating user friendly components and bringing products to life.

## SIDE PROJECTS

- <a href="https://coloringcultures.app/">https://coloringcultures.app/</a>
- <a href="https://journalsyourway.com/">https://journalsyourway.com/</a>
- https://cloudnimi.netlify.app/
- https://freedomactionnow.org/
- <a href="https://github-user-profile-search.netlify.app/">https://github-user-profile-search.netlify.app/</a>

#### **SKILLS & INTERESTS**

#### **Coding Languages**

HTML, CSS, JavaScript

## Frameworks/Systems

React.JS, Typescript, Redux, Bootstrap, Tailwind, Git, Netlify, Chakra UI, SASS, Rest API, Redux, Context API

#### Soft Skills

Problem-solving, team collaboration, critical thinking, relatively fast learner, good command of English, pixel perfect implementation of Figma designs, good coding conventions, project management, leadership roles.

## Others

Figma, WordPress, CMS Made Simple, Squarespace, Webflow, Milanotes, Notion.

## **CONTACT DETAILS**

Email: lilianokeke.ca@gmail.com Github: www.github.com/Lilianada

LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/lilianada
Portfolio: https://lilydesigned.me

# **LILIAN OKEKE**

## FRONTEND DEVELOPER

## HOW TO REACH ME

Email: lilianokeke.ca@gmail.com

Github: www.github.com/Lilianada

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/lilianada

#### **EDUCATIONAL TRAINING**

Nnamdi Azikiwe University, Awka Anambra Nig. BEd in Early Childhood Education

- Enrolled Nov 2017 and graduated Dec 2021
- Taking up specialized courses in Early Child Education
- Vice President of the Final Year Forum

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

- Zuri x I4G Internship Certification
- Udemy Certification for React Js

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCES

- Network Marketer at NeoLife Int'l
- Frontend Developer Freelancer and Intern
- Product Manager at BuildingBloques

I am a front-end web developer with robust problem-solving skills. I am excited to apply for your Front-End Web Development position. I'm passionate about carrying out an outstanding job and have received multiple compliments from my past managers and colleagues for collaborative, quick critical thinking, and logical technical skills to improve work efficiency.

With the skills I have acquired over the years in my previous roles, I am able to translate design wireframes from Figma or Adobe XD into responsive HTML, CSS while also using JavaScript and React for my dynamic and reusable components and adhering to best practices for performance, UX, SEO, and accessibility. I am skilled at writing well-designed, testable, and efficient code using current best practices in Web Development.

I have 2 years of experience with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and React, and 5 years of experience with WordPress, Wix and Squarespace. My keen attention to detail and dedication to solving any problem at hand is what separates me from other candidates with similar qualifications.

For a greater presentation of my background and qualifications, please review my attached resume. I am eager to learn and will greatly appreciate your consideration.

Best Regards,

Lilian Okeke.